Finding Aid for the Allen Sapp Score Collection, circa 1936-1992
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Manuscripts of Works Assigned a "W" Number in Allen Sapp: A Bio-Bibliography, by Alan Green (Greenwood Press, 1996), 1939-1994, I.; Box 1-26 (211 folders)
  - W88 Seven Songs of Carew 1961 (I- II); 1982 (III- VII) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    For tenor voice and piano
    I. Slowly II. Quickly III. Andante IV. Quickly V. Moderately VI. Animated VII. Agitated
    2 paper copies of 1961 vellum holograph, plus pencil holograph, 10 p., of movements III- VII
  - W88 Seven Songs of Carew 1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Ink holograph, annotated, 28 leaves
  - W89 Moral Maxims (30 Songs for Thirty Years) June- July 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Ink holograph, 33 p.
  - W90 Illusions and Affirmations July- August 1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Pencil holograph, 24 leaves.
    Includes annotated title page and typed copies of poems used as text. Missing movement I.
  - W90 Illusions and Affirmations Illusions and Affirmations for Bass Voice and Strings Aug. 25, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    For bass voice and "piano (arranged)"
    Ink holograph, 25 p.
  - W91 Affliction June 29, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    For mezzo-soprano and piano
    Pencil holograph, 18 leaves
  - W92 Set of 12 Canons undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    I. For Sam (violin, viola) II. For Darrell (2 oboes) III. For Jonathan (piano) IV. For Don (flute and cello) V. For Arthur (2 violins, cello) VI. For Karin (soprano and tenor) VII. For Bob (2 violins) VIII. For Fred (piano) IX. For Phil (2 sopranos, B.C.) X. For Joel (piano) XI. For Seamas (2 Cb.) XII. For Allen (viola, bn.)
    Pencil holograph, 9 p.
  - W93 Anoia Jan. 1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    For flute, clarinet, violin, cello, soprano
    Score, ink holograph, 12 p.; 5 parts, ink holograph.
    Includes notes and sketches on separate pages.
  - W94 Two Songs Fall 1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    I. Anonymous Eponymous (title page); Mr. Nobody (1st page of music) II. Riley Set Wryly (title page); The Raggedy Man (1st page of music)
    Pencil holograph, 11 leaves.
    Includes notes, sketches, and letters on separate pages.
  - W95 Dix Chansons Sph"riques 1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    For soprano and piano
    I. Anim" II. Mod"r" III. Lent IV. Anim" et Capricieux V. Langoureux VI. Vite VII. Mouvement" VIII. Agit" IX. Mod"r" X. Anim"
    Pencil holograph, 14 leaves
  - W96 Four Lyrics of Absence and Loss June-July 1983 (I and II), June 27, 1990 (III and IV) (Box 7, Folder 17)
    For contralto, alto flute, violin, celesta, marimba
    I. Lament of Hsi/Ch"n II. The Other Side of the Valley III. Very Quickly IV. Song of Snow-white Heads
    Pencil holograph, 28 leaves.
    Includes ink holograph parts for violin and alto flute, movements III and IV only.
  - W97 Easter Day May 12, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    For SATB chorus, piano
    Ink holograph, annotated, 6 p.
  - W98 Song of Marriage A Song of Marriage | Cantata for Chorus and Chamber Orchestra undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    For SATB chorus, flute, oboe, clarinet in Bb, bassoon, horn in F, 2 violins, viola, cello
    I. The Time of Marriage II. Equality of Persons III. Raising of the Bridegroome IV. Raising of the Bride V. Her Apparelling VI. Going to the Chapelle VII. The Wedding VIII. The Benediction IX. Feasts and Revells X. The Brides Going to Bed XI. The Bridegroome's Coming XII. The Good Night
    Ink holograph, 161 p.
  - W98 Song of Marriage 1948 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    second title page labeled "Work sheets for A Song of Marriage." Pencil and ink sketches and drafts, ca. 100 p.
  - W98 Song of Marriage 1948 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    I-XII, no titles given
    Multilith master of SATB choral score, 21 leaves. Includes 14 paper copies, bound
  - W98 Song of Marriage A Marriage Song 1948 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Ink holograph, vellum, complete orchestra parts only, 52 leaves. Paper copies included
  - W99 In Grato Jubilo In Grato Jubilo | An Occasional Cantata 1949 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    For SSA chorus, chamber orchestra
    I. Hymn (Composed by Irving Fine) II. In Grato Jubilo (Daniel Pinkham) III. Chorale and Fughetta (Gardner Read) IV. Interlude (Allen Sapp) V. Aria for Contralto (Herbert Fromm) VI. Finale (Lukas Foss)
    Bound copy, 87 p. Title page signed by Irving Fine, Gardner Read, and Herbert Fromm
  - W99 In Grato Jubilo IV | Interlude March 1949 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    For flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon, horn, trumpets, trombones, double bass
    Ink holograph, vellum, 11 leaves. Movement IV only of "In Grato Jubilo"
  - W100 Five Landscapes Landscapes | 5 Poems of T.S. Eliot undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    For SSATB Chorus
    I. New Hampshire II. Virginia III. Usk IV. Rannoch by Glencoe V. Quickly
    Pencil holograph, draft, 18 leaves.
    Typed copy of text to "Usk" and "Rannock, by Glencoe" included.
  - W100 Five Landscapes Five Landscapes for acapella Mixed Chorus 1950 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    I. New Hampshire II. Virginia III. Usk IV. Rannoch by Glencoe V. Cape Anne
    Ink holograph, vellum, 16 leaves
  - W100 Five Landscapes Five Landscapes for Acapella Mixed Chorus undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    For SSATB chorus
    multilith master, 45 leaves
  - W100 Five Landscapes Five Landscapes For Acapella Mixed Chorus 1950 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Performance copies. 21 bound copies from vellum master; 36 cm.
  - W100 Five Landscapes Five Landscapes For Acapella Mixed Chorus 1950 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Performance copies. 3 bound copies and 1 unbound copy from vellum master; 28 cm.
  - W101 American Fantasies American Fantasies for Men"s Chorus + 2 Pianos undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    For TTBB chorus, 2 pianos
    Pencil manuscript, draft, 20 leaves. "First Draft" written on title page
  - W102 Little Boy Lost undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    For chorus and unspecified instrumental ensemble
    Pencil manuscript, draft, 43 leaves. Ranges for instrumental ensemble indicated on title page.
  - W102 Little Boy Lost 1953 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    For chorus and unspecified instrumental ensemble.
    I. Overture II. First Invention III. The Laughing Song IV. Second Invention V. First Canzona VI. Third Invention VII. The Little Boy Lost VIII. The Shepherd IX. Fourth Invention X. Fifth Invention XI. Spring XII. The Lilly XIII. Sixth Invention XIV. Second Canzona XV. Epilog: The Rose Tree
    3 bound copies of complete score, 1 annotated
  - W102 Little Boy Lost 1953 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    For chorus and unspecified instrumental ensemble, with parts labeled A, A1, B, B1, C, C1
    multiple copies of instrumental performance parts, in folders labeled 4A-4C1
  - W103 Birthday Piece for A. T. D. Sept. 1953 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    For SSA chorus
    multiple printed copies of choral score, 4 p. each
  - W104 Prayer for Commencement May 1954 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    For SATB chorus
    Multiple printed copies of choral score, 7 p. each
  - W105 Maidens Complaint in Spring-Time 1959 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    For SSA chorus, flute, oboe, English horn, bassoon, two violins, viola, violoncello, contrabass
    Pencil holograph, draft, 18 leaves
  - W105 Maidens Complaint in Spring-Time Summer 1959 (title page); 1959-60 (colophon) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    For SSA chorus, flute, oboe, English horn, bassoon, two violins, viola, violoncello, double bass
    I. "Softly the West Wind blows" II. "Goes forth the Scarlet Spring" II. "Dens for four-footed things" IV. "I see it with my eyes" V. "Alone with thought I sit" VI. "Do thou, O spring most fair"
    Ink holograph, vellum, 68 leaves.
  - W105 Maidens Complaint in Spring-Time Summer 1959 (title page); 1959-60 (colophon) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    I. "Softly the West Wind blows" II. "Goes forth the Scarlet Spring" III. "Dens for four-footed things" IV. "I see it with my eyes" V. "Alone with thought I sit" VI. "Do thou, O spring most fair"
    2 copies from vellum holograph, 1 bound and annotated
  - W105 Maidens Complaint in Spring-Time September 1959 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Multilith master, piano-vocal score, 30 leaves. Multiple bound copies from multilith master included
  - W106 How True Love is Likened to Summer How True Love is Likened to Summer | Morte d'Arthur | Bk. XVIII Chap. 25 Sept.- Oct. 1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    For SATB chorus, 3 trumpets, 3 trombones
    I. Maestoso II. With Spirit and Verve III. Bright and Lively IV. Expressively and Temperately V. Spiteful, Mean, Sharp VI. Tenderly VII. Simple, Expressive VIII. Maestoso
    Ink holograph, vellum, 19 leaves. Extra vellum, ink holograph copies of movements II, VI, and VIII included, wrapped in staff paper with "For Mr. Arthur Fiedler" written on top page.
  - W106 How True Love is Likened to Summer How True Love is Likened to Summer | Morte d'Arthur | Bk. XVIII Chap. 25 | BRASS PARTS 1960 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Ink holograph, 41 p. Complete brass performance parts.
  - W107 Canticum Novum Pro Pace 1962-63 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    For TTBB chorus, flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon, horn
    I. Ritornello A II. Pacem Relinguo Vobis (Communion, Missa Pro Pace) III. Interlude A IV. Da Pacem Domine (Introit, XVIIIth Sunday after Pentecost) V. Interlude B VI. Deus Auctor Pacis (Post-communion, Missa Pro Pace) VII. Interlude C VIII. Da Pacem Domine (Introit, XVIIIth Sunday after Pentecost) IX. Interlude D X. Hodie Nobis de Caelo Pax Vera (Responsory, II Lesson of the Nativity) XI. Ritornello B
    Ink holograph, vellum, 41 leaves
  - W109 Motet, "Er, der Herrlichste von Allen"" undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    For soprano, alto, and tenor voices
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 3 leaves
  - W110 Andante for Orchestra 1941 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    For 3 fl., 3 ob., Eng. hn, 3 cl., b. cl., 2 bn., cbn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 3 tbn., t., timp., strings, harp
    Ink holograph, annotated, 18 p.
  - W110 Andante for Orchestra undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Ink manuscript, annotated, 32 p.
  - W110 Andante for Orchestra undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    printed performance parts, each stamped "Mario Carmosino | 1179 | Local No. 9 | Registered 1939"
  - W110 Andante for Orchestra undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    2 ink holograph title pages: The first is inscribed "To Grace Ann Hubbard | Two Movements for Orchestra | by | Allen D. Sapp Jr. | 1941." The second is inscribed "To | Grace Ann Hubbard | Andante for Orchestra | 1941 | by | Allen Sapp Jr."
  - W111 Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra Concertino No. 1 August 1942 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    For solo piano, fl., ob., cl., bn., 2 hn., tpt., strings
    I. Allegro II. Passacaglia On a Theme by Piston III. Allegro
    Ink holograph, vellum, 88 leaves
  - W111 Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra Concertino No. 1 undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    For solo piano, fl., ob., cl., bn., 2 hn., tp., strings
    Ink holograph orchestra parts, annotated.
  - W111 Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra Concertino: III undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    Pencil holograph, draft, 18 p. Movement III only.
  - W111 Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra Passacaglia on a Theme by Piston 1942 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    For fl., ob., cl., bn., 2 hn., tpt., tbn., timp., strings (no piano part notated)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 13 p. Movement II of Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra.
  - W111 Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra Passacaglia on a Theme by Piston July 1942 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    For piano, fl., ob., cl., bn., 2 hn., tpt., timp., strings
    Ink holograph, annotated, 16 p. Movement II of Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra.
  - W111 Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra Passacaglia on a Theme by Piston undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    For piano, fl., ob., cl., bn., 2 hn., tpt., timp., strings (no trombone)
    Ink manuscript parts, for piano, winds, brass and timpani. Photocopies of string parts. Movement II of Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra.
  - W111 Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra Passacaglia on a Theme by Piston 1942 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    Ink holograph, 3 p. Movement II of Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra.
  - W111 Concertino for Piano and Chamber Orchestra Concertino undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
    Pencil and ink manuscript, 17 p. Sketches and drafts.
  - W112 Suite for Orchestra, no. 1 Suite for Orchestra 1949 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    For 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 cl., 2 bn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 3 tbn., piano, harp, strings
    I. Fanfare II. Ode III. Scherzo IV. Elegy V. Finale
    Pencil holograph, draft, 60 leaves
  - W112 Suite for Orchestra, no. 1 Suite for Orchestra undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    For 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 cl., 2 bn., Eng. Hn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 3 tbn., piano, harp, strings
    Ink manuscript parts, vellum. Flute I and II, oboe I and II, English Horn, clarinet I and II, bassoon I and II, horn I (partial), only
  - W112 Suite for Orchestra, no. 1 Suite for Orchestra 1949 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    For arrangement for piano 4 hands
    Ink holograph, vellum, 39 leaves
  - W113 Suite for Orchestra, no. 2 Second Suite for Orchestra 1952 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    For picc., 2 fl., 2 ob., Eng. Hn., 2 bn., cbn., 2 cl., b. cl., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 2 tbn., b. tbn., t., piano, harp, strings
    Pencil holograph, draft, 34 leaves
  - W113 Suite for Orchestra, no. 2 1952-1956 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    I. Andante Mesto II. Allegro Giocoso III. Adagietto IV. Allegro Molto
    Ink holograph, vellum, 95 leaves
  - W114 Double Image 1957 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    For picc., 2 fl., 2 ob., Eng. Hn., 2 cl., b. cl., 2 bn., cbn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 2 tbn., b. tbn., t., timp., perc., celeste, piano, harp, strings
    Ink holograph, vellum, 59 leaves. Bound paper copy included.
  - W114 Double Image The Double Image | Overture for Orchestra 1956-57 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Pencil holograph, reduced score, annotated, 13 leaves
  - W114 Double Image 1957 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    For picc., 2 fl., 2 ob., Eng. hn., 2 cl.., b. cl., 2 bn., cbn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 2 tbn., b. tbn., t., timp., perc., celeste, piano, harp, strings
    Vellum parts, incomplete orchestration. Paper parts, complete.
    Includes typed note on Florida State University School of Music letter- head, listing "Parts received from Mr. Sapp on September 5, 1978 (for performance November 4, 1978)".
  - W115 Overture, "The Women of Trachis" Nov. 1960 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    For 2 ob., 2 hn., strings
    Ink holograph, vellum, 50 leaves
  - W116 June June 8, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    For fl., ob., cl., bn., hn., strings
    I. Allegro Molto II. Poco Scherzando III. Andantino IV. Adagio V. Poco Scherzando
    Ink holograph, vellum, 110 leaves
  - W116 June June 8, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    bound paper score made from vellum ink holograph, annotated
  - W116 June June 8, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    complete instrumental parts, paper, annotated
  - W117 Colloquies I Colloquies 1963 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    For piano, string orchestra
    I. Larghetto II. Allegro Molto III. Larghetto IV. Allegro Molto
    Ink holograph, vellum, 47 leaves
  - W117 Colloquies I Colloquies 1963 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    For arrangement for 2 pianos
  - W117 Colloquies I Colloquies 1963 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Ink holograph string parts: violin I and II, viola, violoncello, contrabass. Reproductions included: 9 violin I, 6 violin II, 4 viola, 8 violincello, 2 contrabass.
  - W118 Imaginary Creatures: A Bestiary for the Credulous Imaginary Creatures undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    For solo harpsichord, 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 cl., 2 bn., 2 hn., strings
    I. Halcyons II. Basilisk III. Unicorn IV. Phoenix V. Chiron
    Pencil manuscript, draft, 41 p.
    "Imaginary Conversations" also written on title page, in ink.
  - W118 Imaginary Creatures: A Bestiary for the Credulous Imaginary Creatures 1981 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    I. Halcyons II. Basilisk III. Unicorn IV. Phoenix V. Centaurs
    Pencil holograph, 70 p.
    Typed program notes included; "Imaginary Conversations" written in ink on preliminary page.
  - W119 Crennelations 1982 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    For tenor solo, solo violin obbligato, 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 cl., 2 bn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 3 tbn., t., perc., strings
    Ink holograph, 135 p.
    Includes program notes, in preliminary pages and colophon.
  - W119 Crennelations undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    material related to composition and premier of Crennelations: Programs and program notes, sketches labeled "vocal lines," "music encipherment"
  - W119 Crennelations undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    For tenor solo, solo violin obbligato, 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 cl., 2 bn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 3 tbn., tuba, perc., strings
    Ink holograph, complete string parts only
  - W119 Crennelations 1982 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    For arrangement for voice and piano
    Ink holograph, 48 p. Includes 1 bound photocopy.
  - W119 Crennelations 1982 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Ink holograph, 135 p. photocopy of score in Box 18, Folder 3, with marginalia and performance markings.
  - W119 Crennelations undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    For orchestra: tenor solo, solo violin obbligato, 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 cl., 2 bn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 3 tbn., t., perc., strings
    Ink holograph parts; wind, brass, and percussion only. Individual lines of music for most parts "cut and pasted" together.
  - W119 Crennelations undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    bound photocopies of ink holograph parts
  - W121 Xenon Ciborium Ciborium | Xenon Summer 1985 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    For Reduced score. Original instrumentation listed on title page: 3 fl., alto fl., 3 ob., Eng. Hn., Eb cl., 3 Bb cl., b. cl., contrabass cl., 3 bn., cbn., 6 hn., Eb tpt., 2 C tpt., 2 Bb tpt., 3 tbn., b. tbn., 2 t., harp, celesta, perc., strings
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 12 leaves
  - W121 Xenon Ciborium Summer 1985 (title page); 1982-1985(colophon) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    For orchestral: 3 fl., alto fl., 3 ob., Eng. Hn., Eb cl., 3 Bb cl., b. cl., contrab. cl.., 3 bn., 6 hn., Eb tpt., 2 C tpt., 2 Bb tpt., 3 tbn., b. tbn., 2 t., harp, celesta, perc., strings
    copy of holograph, cut and pasted onto plain 11" X 17" paper, 19 p.
  - W121 Xenon Ciborium 1985 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    complete parts, ink holograph. Multiple copies of string parts.
  - W123 Short Concerto for Piano and Chamber Orchestra 1939 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    For piano, 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 clar., 2 bn., 2 horns, 2 trpt., strings
    I. Allegro Molto II. Andante Lyrico III. Presto
    Ink holograph, annotated, 36 p. Unfinished.
  - W123 Concerto for Piano and Orchestra 1940 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    For piano, 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 cl., 2 bn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 2 tbn., strings
    I. Allegro Molto II. Andante con Expressione III. Presto
    Ink holograph, 74 pages. Unfinished.
  - W124 Concerto for Piano in One Movement 1942 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    For piano, 3 fl., 3 ob., 3 cl., 3 bn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 3 tbn, t., perc., timp., strings
    Ink holograph, 16 p. Unfinished.
  - W125 Introduction and Allegro for Violin and Orchestra 1942 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    For solo violin, 2 fl., 2 ob., 3 cl., 2 bn., 4 hn., 3 tpt., 3 tbn., timp., piano, strings
    I. Introduction II. Allegro
    Ink holograph, 19 p. Unfinished.
  - W125 Introduction and Allegro for Violin and Orchestra undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    For solo violin, piano
    Pencil holograph, sketches, 9 leaves
  - W126 Intermezzo for Orchestra 1950 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    For orchestra, unspecified
    Pencil holograph, draft, 10 leaves. Unfinished.
  - W126 Intermezzo for Orchestra 1950 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    For arrangement for piano
    Pencil holograph, 6 leaves + 2 p.
    "Intermezzo II" written at bottom of title page.
  - W127 Heptagon The Heptagon (title page); The Septagon (caption) 1957-1959 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Pencil holograph, draft, 2 leaves; ink holograph, vellum, 26 leaves.
    Unfinished, includes notes on graph and lined paper.
  - W128 Colloquies III 1981 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    For wind ensemble: piano, fl., ob., cl., bn., 2 hn., 2 tpt., tbn., tuba
    Ink holograph parts, no piano. Photcopies included.
  - W128 Colloquies III 1981 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    For wind ensemble: piano, fl., ob., cl., bn., 2 hn., 2 tpt., tbn., t.
    Photocopy of manuscript score, 22 leaves, each leaf cut in half.
  - W128 Colloquies III undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
    parts, cut and pasted from photocopies of manuscript parts
  - W129 Fanfare for WGUC Jan. 1982 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    For brass ensemble
    Pencil holograph, 1 p.
    Includes typed note acknowledging receipt of music, and listing when performance would occur.
  - W130 Cheektowaga and Tonawanda Divisions 1983 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    text notes and row form sketches, 3 p.
  - W130 Cheektowaga and Tonawanda Divisions 1983 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    For wind ensemble: picc., 2 fl., 2 ob., Eb cl., 6 Bb cl., bass cl., contrab. cl.., 2 bn., sop. sax, alto sax, tenor sax., bari. sax., 4 hn., 4 tpt., 4 tbn., euph., 2 t., perc.
    Ink holograph, 125 p. Program notes in preliminary pages and colophon.
  - W130 Cheektowaga and Tonawanda Divisions 1983 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    2 photocopies of ink holograph score.
    Received from former UB band director, Frank Cipolla.
  - W130 Cheektowaga and Tonawanda Divisions 1983 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Ink holograph parts, complete
  - W131 Four Winds 1984 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    For wind ensemble, reduced score.
    I. Notos II. Boreas III. Zephyros IV. Euros
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 30 leaves.
    Each movement in individual file folder, sketches and 12-tone material (matrix, row forms) included.
  - W131 Four Winds 1984 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    For wind ensemble: picc., 2 fl., 2 ob., Eb cl., 6 Bb cl., b. cl., contrab. clar., 2 bn., sop. sax., alto sax., tenor sax., bari. sax., 4 hn., 4 tpt., 4 tbn., euph., 2 t., perc.
    I. Notos (The South Wind) II. Boreas (The North Wind) III. Zephyros (The West Wind) IV. Euros (The East Wind)
    Ink holograph, 105 leaves.
    Descriptive material ("A Geneology of the Winds") on title page; Cincinnati Wind Ensemble part assignments list taped to verso of title page.
  - W131 Four Winds 1984 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Bound photocopy of ink holograph, 105 leaves.
  - W132 Cincinnati Morality and Consolation 1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    For wind ensemble: picc., 2 fl., alto fl., 4 ob., Eb cl., 6 Bb cl., b. cl., contrab. cl., 3 bn., cbn., alto sax., tenor sax., bari. sax., 4 hn, 6 tpt., 4 tbn., bass tbn., euph., 4 t.
    Ink holograph, vellum, 68 leaves
  - W132 Cincinnati Morality and Consolation 1985 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    For wind ensemble, reduced score
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 25 leaves
  - W132 Cincinnati Morality and Consolation undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    44 bound photocopies of parts
  - W121 Xenon Ciborium Summer 1985 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    For 3 fl., alto fl., 3 ob., Eng. Hn., Eb cl., 3 Bb cl., b. cl., contrab. cl., 3 bn., 6 hn., Eb tpt., 2 C tpt., 2 Bb tpt., 3 tbn., bass tbn., 2 t., harp, celesta, perc., strings
    Ink holograph, vellum, 15" X 20", 19 leaves
  - W121 Xenon Ciborium Summer 1985 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    bound photocopy of vellum holograph in Box 26, Folder 1; annotated
  - W121 Xenon Ciborium Summer 1985 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Ink holograph, 15" X 20", annotated, 19 leaves
  - W126 Intermezzo for Orchestra 1949 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Pencil holograph, 19" X 12", 4 p. Unfinished.
- Manuscripts of Titled Works Not Assigned a "W" Number, 1938-1948, II.; Box 27-28 (53 folders)
  Manuscripts which appear to have annotations made by someone other than Sapp have "corrections" and/or "comments" listed in the Notes field.
  Arranged alphabetically by title of work.
  - All Day I Hear, March 18, 1941 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    For TTBB Chorus
    Ink holograph, unfinished, 4 p.
  - All Day I Hear | (Revised and amended), undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Ink holograph, 2 p. Corrections, red ink
  - Allegro for String Quartet, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
    For string quartet
    Ink holograph, 1 p. + 2 measures, unfinished
  - Andante for Eng. Horn, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    For solo Eng. hn.
  - Canon for Four Voices in C Major, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    For SATB voices